BENEDIKTA NDUUVA NGWEESHIMWENE SHIKESHO

Address: PO Box 11412, Oshakati, Namibia Telephone: +264 81 7171813 / +264 81 2132556

Email: nduuvas@gmail.com

Profile

I am an energetic, ambitious person who has developed a mature and responsible approach to any task that I undertake. I have good communication and interpersonal skills. I believe in hard work, perseverance, commitment, innovation and creativity. As a graduate with around 3 years in the Tourism industry and having worked with different people from different backgrounds, I have great ability of working in a team in order to execute tasks presented to the team. I am a fast leaner and I have unwavering desire to become better everyday.

Personal Details

Sex: Female
Age: 28
Marital Status: Single
Nationality: Namibian

Languages: English, Oshiwambo

Education

Institution: Namibia University of Science and Technology

Qualification: Bachelor of Tourism Management

Majors: Tourism Management

Year completed: 2016

School: Mweshipandeka High School

Qualification: National Senior Certificate (NSC)

Subjects English, Oshindonga, Mathematics, Biology, Geography, Physical Science

Year completed: 2011

Special Certificates

Certificate: Time Management

Awarding body: Harvard Business Review

Date awarded: July 2018

Certificate(s): Communication seminar, Leadership seminar, Hospitality seminar, Diversity

seminar

Awarding body: Disney Animal, Science and Environment

Date awarded: July 2018

Experience

Company: Walt Disney Parks and Resorts (Orlando, Florida, United States of America) **Position:** Disney Animals, Science and Environment educator (Savannah Guide)

Period: 10 August 2017 to 01 August 2018

Key responsibilities: seek out guests to promote my cultural heritage, country and the African continent at large. Engaging guests in informal conversations on topics such as wildlife, animal behaviour, animal care and conservation. Engaging in wildlife oriented activities with children. Developing and delivering structured presentations on my culture and the wildlife of Africa, which are both educational and engaging. Ensuring guests safety with the animals. Adjusting

conversations with contents to a variety of age levels. Increasing my knowledge regarding wildlife and conservation related issues and sharing with guests. Conducting resort activities such as guided tours of the hotel and evening stories. Delivering entertaining and engaging traditional African folktales. Providing Animal Kingdom Lodge and Walt Disney Resort information to guests. Maintaining Disney show quality and guests standards in workplace (including backstage areas). Supporting training of all fellow cast members.

Company: Elite Travel Planners (Pty) Ltd

Position: Travel Consultant

Period: 01 August 2016 to 31 July 2017

Key responsibilities: making quotations and booking air tickets, accommodation, car rentals, holiday packages, travel insurance and issuing air tickets. Checking in passengers online before traveling, handling corporate client bookings and private bookings, attending to phone calls and emails.

Company:HRG Rennies Travel NamibiaPosition:Junior Travel Consultant (Intern)Period:12 August 2015 to 13 January 2016

Key responsibilities: receptionist: operating the switchboard phone, assisting and directing clients to correct consultants, collecting and organising ticket coupons and folding immigration forms. Sales, Marketing and Finance: making accommodation and car rental vouchers and looking for tenders.

Operations (travel consultant): preparing air quotations and accommodation quotations, booking air tickets, checking the booking queues daily to make sure that all booking are attended to accordingly and quoting holiday packages.

Company: Hotel Destiny Ongwediva

Position: Front desk, Housekeeping, Kitchen and restaurant

Period: 28 November 2014 to 28 January 2015

Key responsibilities: Receptionist: attend to the phone calls, make accommodation quotations and book rooms accordingly, help book events (that will be held at the hotel) and check guests in and out of their rooms.

Cleaning lady: attending to the rooms and making sure that they are clean before guests check in, washing and ironing sheets and guests clothes, proving guests with clean sheets and toiletries, cleaning bar and restaurant restrooms.

Cook: helped the chefs in preparing different food orders, washing and packing kitchen utensils, packing ingredients to assure that the freezer, store room and the kitchen are neat and tidy.

Key Skills

- Teamwork
- Excellent Customer Service
- Computer skills (Excel, PowerPoint, Word)

Key Achievements

- Savannah guide trainer
- Youth choir time keeper

Interests and activities

I enjoy singing and dancing, traveling and listening to music, watching sports and participating in outdoor activities.

Actively involved in church as a choir member (we help clean the church and prepare Holly Mass service and visit those who are in need such as old age, help orphans and the poor and visit prisoners).

References

Reference 1

Ms. Katy Krezo, Education manager: Disney's Animal Kingdom Lodge

Tell: +1 (407) 9384746 / cell: +1 (407) 4131080

Email: katy.krezo@disney.com

Reference 2

Mr. Andre Mattheyse, Branch manager: HGR Rennies Travel Namibia

Tell: +264 61 2890760 / cell: +264 81 128 7947 Email: Andre.Mattheyse@rennies.hrgworldwide.com

Reference 3

Mrs Isobel Manuel, Lecturer: department of Hospitality and Tourism

Tell: +264 61 207 2335 Email: igreen@nust.na